Let us now look at syntax and runtime errors
when manipulating data, which means one is
trying to insert, update, or delete data.
I have a query here that is looking to add
two records to a BikeRepairs table.
I will execute the query.
There is a syntax error near the number 1.
With queries, it is not hard to miss a keyword
or two at times.
The VALUES keyword is missing.
I will add that where it needs to go and then
execute this query again.
The syntax errors are gone, but now we have
a runtime error.
The error basically says we cannot duplicate
a primary key entry.
I'm going to quickly add a SELECT statement
below this to select everything from the BikeRepairs
table, and sure enough, these two values for
BikeRepairID are already used.
Seeing that these records have already been
entered, I do not need to run this INSERT
statement again.
That said, you have now seen both syntax and
runtime errors for data manipulation queries.
Throughout this course, you have learned how
to organize, build, enter data into, and retrieve
data from a database.
With this knowledge, you are set up well for
the IT Specialist Databases exam, which, when
passed, will get you the IT Specialist Databases
certification.
This course will also help improve your employability.
Thank you for taking this course, and good
luck with your exam.